CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

Solutions Engineer

832 - 439 - 3705



Cesar.sanchezvegas82@gmail.com



Atlanta. GA



linkedin.com/in/cesarsanchezvegas



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly motivated and experienced pre-sales executive with proven history of achieving targets and delivering results. In depth operating knowledge on core banking platforms, digital banking platforms and check processing. Proficient in front-end and back-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Firebase, Node JS, MySQL, GitHub and Docker.

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Excellent Communication Skills

Excellent Problem-Solving abilities

Strategic Planning and Management

Coach and Trainer

Vendor and Partner Management

Analytics Skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOLUTIONS ENGINEER AND LATIN AMERICA SALES EXECUTIVEVSoft Corp | Duluth, GA | 2016 - Present

- Prepare and perform sales presentation and demonstration to prospect and existing customers as the Subject Matter Expert for VSoft Core Banking system for US activities and VSoft Check Processing Platform for LATAM activities.
- Answer Request for Proposal and create Business Proposals,
 Statements of Work and any other documents required during the sale cycle for VSoft Core Banking and VSoft Check Processing initiatives.
- Perform Gap and system architecture analysis on Core Banking systems such as Fiserv-DNA, Fiserv-Portico, Finastra-Sparak, Corelation-Keystone, and other Core, report finding and create a new proposed system architecture to prospect customers during the sales cycle.
- Perform analysis in the designing, defining and documenting the VSoft Remittance Solution, VSoft Real-Time Signature Verification, VSoft Positive Pay, Fiserv-DNA RTP integration through Kony and direct AFS integration.
- Define requirements (BRDs, SRDs, etc.) to integrate with customers and partner solutions either through API Calls, REST web services or extract files.

BRANCH MANAGER, VP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2014 - 2016

- Managed daily operations of a \$60 million branch banking facility, including developing strategies to increase deposit and investment balances, managing the monthly budget and recruiting/retention of employees (six).
- Exceed goals and expectations in all measurable categories while growing balances by 25% YOY.

CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

System Integration

System Architecture

Development of Test Scripts

Junior Engineer

Banking Technology Specialist

Banking Operations Specialist

EXTRAS

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English and Spanish

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

- Evaluated branch performance and implement actions to ensure objectives were met while strengthening and growing customer relationships through a commitment to quality service.
- Trained team to focus on Customer Satisfaction improving behaviors, which has resulted in the branch being among the top 10% in customer service satisfaction nationwide (Q4 100% Satisfaction)

ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER, AVP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2010 - 2014

- Managed, coached and developed sales and service team to maintain an operationally sound branch (total Net Operating Losses for three consecutive years – the lowest in the market.)
- Executed and provided guidance on sales activities with sales and service team helping increase balances and referrals.
- Consistently among the top 10% YOY in customer service satisfaction.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

BRANCH MANAGER
ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER
FINANCIAL SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE
SunTrust Bank | Atlanta, GA | 2008 – 2010

EDUCATION

CODING BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,
jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, Docker & GitHub.

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN FINANCE: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

B.B.A. IN ECONOMICS: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA **B.B.A. IN FINANCE**: University of Houston/Downtown, Houston, TX